# JUAN BRUNO | Computer Scientist

# Senior Software Engineer – Lead Developer



Email: juan.marcos.bruno@gmail.com

Phone: +34 644 314 661

# **Career Summary**

Senior Software Engineer in the development and maintenance of an ecosystem of microservices for *Payroll Calculations* BU in *Personio* (<u>www.personio.de</u>), also recently involved in Cloud design, architecture and implementation of social networks' features for the *Poppulo Harmony* platform (www.poppulo.com).

Formerly the Lead Software Developer for the Batch Solutions Team in Equifax; design, architecture and implementation of a fully Cloud-Based Big Data application.

Worked previously on Cloud Microservices architectures, utilizing Java (functional and non-functional) and Spring framework's family of modules. Further back in my career have also participated in the development of Post Trade software, J2EE compliant JAVA applications, as well as in the development of Java and GRAILS RESTful APIs.

Creator of the course 'Master Big Data with Apache Spark and Java' on the Educative e-learning platform: <a href="https://www.educative.io/courses/mastering-big-data-apache-spark-java-api">https://www.educative.io/courses/mastering-big-data-apache-spark-java-api</a>

Tech Skills and Experience			Cloud Experience
Java 18. Python     3.10. Kotlin	<ul> <li>Relational DBs (Post- greSQL, MySQL, Oracle)</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Apache Spark on AWS EMR</li> </ul>	AWS Solutions     Architect
<ul> <li>Spring Framework</li> <li>Design and Enterprise Patterns</li> </ul>	<ul><li>JPA. JooQ</li><li>Microservices Architectures</li></ul>	<ul><li>AWS</li></ul>	<ul><li>AWS Step Functions</li><li>AWS DynamoDB</li></ul>
<ul> <li>TDD</li> <li>GraphQL,         REST/SOAP, Web         Services</li> <li>XML, JSON Processing</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Cucum- ber/JUnit5/Mockito</li> <li>NoSQL Databases (Cassandra, DynamoDB)</li> <li>Agile Methodologies</li> <li>Git/SVN/Gitlab</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>AWS RDS (Postgres DB engine)</li> <li>AWS Lambda         Serverless Functions</li> <li>AWS Cloud-         Watch</li> <li>IaC. Terraform.         CDK.</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>AWS DynamoDB</li> <li>AWS Fargate.         EC2 VMs on         ECS.</li> <li>AWS S3</li> <li>Cloud and Infra         Architecture</li> <li>SNS/SQS</li> </ul>

#### Languages

Spanish (Native speaker) English (Fluent)

# Career History

**Senior Software Engineer** Sept 2023 – Present.

Personio, Business Unit: Payroll—Fully Remote Within the EU Company based in Munich, Germany.

**Project:** Payroll Calculations. Backend developer and AWS Consultant. Worked on developments for three key microservices (Orchestration, calculations and storage) related to payroll calculations for the German market.

Tech Stack: Kotlin Microservices, Spring Boot, JooQ, SQS/SNS, PostgreSQL:, Datadog, Mokk, Kotlinx, Gitlab.

Senior Software Engineer – Cloud Engineer (AWS) Sept 2021 – Sept 2023. Poppulo, Business Unit: People Management – Fully Remote Within the EU Company based in Cork, Ireland.

**Project:** Peoples' Management Microservices. Full-stack developer, full hands-on on all the different aspects of the software development lifecycle, i.e. design, backend development, testing, CI/CD pipelines configuration/monitoring, continuous deployment.

 Tech Stack: Scala/Java Microservices, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Kafka, Cassandra, AWS Keyspaces, MySQL, Grafana, Kibana, Prometheus, Cucumber, Gitlab.

**Project:** <u>Poppulo Harmony Platform.</u> AWS-Based Cloud architecture and Design, alongside implementation of @Mentions feature for comments, posts, feeds.

• Cloud Tech Stack: AWS Lambda, AWS Fargate, AWS OpenSearch, AWS Kinesis (Streams).

### **Lead Software Developer** Mar 2019 – Sep 2021

Equifax, Business Unit: Collections & Recoveries - Dublin, Ireland.

Design, Architecture and Implementation of a fully Cloud Based Big Data solution for batch processing of collections and recoveries datasets. Re engineering of the Batch Jobs and Satellite Services products from a Legacy solution into the AWS Platform by following a multi tenancy model of cloud infrastructure and resources. As a Technical Lead responsibilities included driving agile ceremonies (Scrum), mentoring other developers on the team and engaging in conversation with BAs and POs around requirements.

- Spring Core, JPA and Spring Cloud Microservices' modules for satellite services interacting with the Product, as well as services backing UI products.
- AWS Services: EMR, Step Functions, DynamoDB, RDS PostgresSQL, AWS API Gateway, Lambda Functions, EC2 on ECS and S3.
- Apache Spark Java API for Big Data processing.
- Agile Methodology: Scrum/Spotify Model.
- Git, Maven. CD/Cl: Github, Jenkins on cloud virtualized servers with blue-green deployments.
- Frontend: Angular 2, TypeScript, NodeJS/Javascript.
- Testing: Cucumber, Spock Framework, Mockito, Mocked Lambda Functions and Environments.

#### Sr. Software Engineer Feb 2018 – Mar 2019

Equifax, Business Unit: The Workforce Number (https://www.theworknumber.com) - Dublin, Ireland.

Development of Synchronous Microservices for the *Instant Verification Services* Product. Solution for processing and servicing Employment/Career History information.

- Spring Boot and Spring Restful modules, Spring Cloud modules (Eureka, Config server and client, Zuul Gateway, etc.). Spring Data JPA/JDBC Template for the persistence layer.
- Oauth2 and Spring Security, OpenId connect based implementation. HashiCorp Vault.
- Oracle SQL.
- Git, Maven and Gradle. CD/CI: Jenkins and cloud virtualized servers.

# Software Engineer Aug 2014 – Feb 2018

IHS Markit, Dublin, Ireland

Post Trade Software Enterprise Application for processing movements on companies' announcements around Securities. Development included Integration of heterogeneous applications through backend modules and web services, coupled with the use of an in-house propriety ESB, JMS messaging and batch processing capabilities (Spring Batch.)

- Java EE Core Technologies: Servlets, Enterprise Java Beans (EJB 3.x), JDBC and JPA (Hibernate Implementation).
- Oracle 11g DBMS and PL/SQL scripting.
- Java RESTful web services developments.
- Frameworks: Spring batch, Freemarker (Frontend) and lately AngularJS.
- SVN versioning, Crucible, Bamboo integration, Jira.
- Test Driven Development, JMock, Mockito.

Java Backend Developer Jan 2014 – Aug 2014 MercadoLibre (www.mercadolibre.com) Buenos Aires, Argentina

Enhancements and migration from legacy code (re-engineering) for the billing APIs used and consumed by the accounting integrated systems. The site is the most successful e-commerce application in South America. Developments were focused mainly on creation of RESTful web services and maintenance for the legacy Jersey web services as well. RESTful API implementation in Grails/Groovy and Java EE Jersey Web services legacy code maintenance. Implementation of NoSQL technology for the persistence layer (Document oriented):

- RESTful API designs in Grails/Groovy and Java EE Jersey Web services.
- Oracle 11g DBMS and PL/SQL scripting.
- Java integration with ElasticSearch for text storing and processing. Java (J2EE) legacy billing systems maintenance.
- Git, Gerrit, Github.
- TDD, Spock framework.

### **Java Backend Developer** May 2013-Jan

2014 Verizon Buenos Aires, Argentina

Middleware application developments, focusing on the integration of heterogeneous systems through common interfaces. The SOA architecture was enriched by implementing a virtualized layer and utilizing OSB (Oracle Service Bus). On the Java technical level this involved working mostly with Oracle's framework capabilities but also SOAP and XML based java web services (JAX-WS/JAXB and the usage of Java Enterprise APIs for the business/service and persistence layers(JMS, EJB, JPA-EclipseLink implementation):

- Backend/Middleware Developer JAVA EE, Oracle PL/SQL, XML, JMS, EJB, JPA.
- SOAP based Web Services development. XML processing through XSLT, XPATH and XQUERY.
- Oracle Service Bus (OSB, Oracle Enterprise Service Bus) management and usage: Services virtualization, routing, security, etc.
- Continuous Integration through HP Quality Centre and Hudson.

#### Other Past Work Experience

**Junior Java Developer** Jun 2012-Apr 2013 Sabre Holdings (Travelocity) Buenos Aires, Argentina

**Programming Intern** Dec 2009-May 2010 Superior Council of Catholic Education (CONSUDEC) Buenos Aires, Argentina

# **EDUCATION**

**BSc in Computing Science** Aug 2014 – Sep 2016

Griffith College - Dublin, Ireland

**BSc in Systems Engineering** Sep 2008 – May 2013 Universidad Nacional de La Matanza (UNLAM) - San Justo, Argentina

**Philosophy and Spanish Language Major** Sep 2002 – May 2006 Universidad de Buenos Aires (UBA) - Buenos Aires, Argentina